John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Corporate Structure, RG 1 FA1793
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Trustees, 1950-2019; 1; 33.99 Cubic Feet 87 letter document boxes and 5 half-letter boxes
  - Meetings, 1950-2019; 6; 11.01 Cubic Feet 28 letter document boxes, 2 half-letter box
    - Meeting Minutes, 1950-2019; 3
      - Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Items for discussion include: reports by the Finance Committee, a Management and Organizational Structure Study by Ed Hamilton (includes a report-Portrait of Desired Generic Characteristics), President's Report, Distribution Committee report, Nominating Committee report, Presidential Search committee report (September), Human Resources and Administration report (December). The September meeting reports the appointment of Penelope McPhee as vice president and chief program officer.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Topics covered include: Finance Committee report, Treasurer's report, Human Resources and Administration Committee Report (Belinda Lawrence joins staff), Planning and Program Committee report, President's Report (death of C.C. Gibson), staff retreat, Distribution Committee report, letter from John Ong to Gerald Austen re: the Community Initiatives program in relation to the sales and acquisitions of newspapers by Knight Ridder, memo on same subject from Alvah Chapman, list of issues for discussion related to Knight Ridder sales and acquisitions, resolutions re: C.C. Gibson and approval of emergency grants in Grand Forks, ND, and 1997/98 budget.
      - Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
        Eleven (11) original Knight communities. Items for discussion include: reports by the Finance Committee, Pension Committee, Treasurer, Administrative and Human Resources Committee, the President (Hodding Carter joins foundation as president), the Distribution Committee (list of approved grants included), Nominating Committee, the Chairman, and the Planning and Program Committee, a Resolution for Archive and Document Management Policy (March), a Trustee List, 1998 Committee Appointments, a Resolution and Recommendations from the Planning Committee for Operating in Communities Without Advisors, a Memorandum from General Counsel on Community Initiatives Funding in Knight Ridder Cities, and an Attachment from General Counsel on Self-dealing Issues and Knight Foundation's Relationship with Knight Ridder (June). Eleven original Knight Communities/cities. 2 folders
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        Topics include reports from the Grants Review Committee, Human Resources and Administration Committee, Nominating Committee, Planning and Program Committee, a resolution for the Flexible Benefits Plan (September), President's Report, Treasurer's Report, the Foundation's 50th Anniversary celebration, and strategic planning (December). Resolution on naming structures after the Knight Brothers only. Conflict of Interest Policy Memo from Rod Petrey.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 March 14 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Topics include announcement of the death of Lee Hills, appointment of new trustee John Rogers, reports of the Grants Review Committee, Finance Committee, Treasurer's Report, Human Resources and Administration Committee, Pension Plan Administrative and Investment Committees, Planning and Program Committee, Nominating Committee, an overview of the Community Initiatives Program, overview of the Arts and Culture Program, Resolution to Revise the Foundation's 403b Plan, Resolution for the Foundation's Retirement Plan, and 2000 Committee Appointments.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 June 12-13 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        The file holds minutes for a special meeting of the Board of Trustees, held in order to review grant requests from organizations based in Akron, OH. The quarterly meeting of the Board was held the next day. Included in the minutes are a list of approved grants, and reports from the Finance Committee, the Treasurer, the Administrative and Human Resources Committee, the Nominating Committee and the President. An overview of the evaluation program, a resolution concerning the pension restoration, the retirement plan agreement, and recommendation for trustee tenure are included as appendices.Adoption of a non-exclusion policy in the Foundation's grant making.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 September 10 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        The file holds minutes for the quarterly meeting of the Board of Trustees, held in Miami, FL on 9/10/2000. New trustees Alvarez and Grogan were nominated, planning for the Foundation's 50th anniversary was discussed, and a resolution was adopted on the appointment of officers.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2000 December 5 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        The file holds minutes for the quarterly meeting of the Board of Trustees, held in Miami, FL on 12/5/2000. New trustees Alvarez and Grogan were welcomed. The new strategic plan was discussed (Planning and Program committee reported), and attachments include the 2001 Transition budget, by-laws, and the strategic plan. Issues regarding the 401K plan, matching contributions and pension plans were discussed.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2001 March-June (Box 6, Folder 4)
        Minutes for the annual meeting of the Board of Trustees, held in Miami, FL on March 13, 2001. The Planning and Program Committee Chair, Jill Conway, reported on implementation of the strategic plan. The Finance Committee Chair, Gordon Heffern, reported on 2000 performance of the Foundation's assets and investments. The Administrative and Human Resources Committee Chair, John Ong, reported on a number of administrative and staffing issues. Also included is the President's Report, a review of grants approved, and a copy of the Strategic Plan, 2000 - 2005. The June minutes report on a special meeting (to consider South Florida grants) and a regular quarterly meeting, both held in Miami, on June 11th and 12th, respectively. Included is an update on the implementation of the Community Partners Program, a Program Initiative Expense Summary, an administrative budget report, and a grant spending analysis.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2001 September-December (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Minutes of the quarterly meetings of the trustees of the Knight Foundation held in Miami, Florida. Included in the September 11 minutes are memos re: a community foundation assessment tool, Foundation responses to discrimination policies, a Community Partners Program update, and the amended 403(b) plan. The minutes for the December meeting contains attachments on: Recommendations for the 2002 Program Budgets, Community Partners update, the grants review committee meeting minutes of November 26, 2001, and a current organization chart,
      - Meeting Minutes, 2002 March 11 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami, Florida on March 11, 2002. Included is a proposal to establish a National Center on College Sports and Education, a comparison of three buildings considered in the Foundation's move, an incentive plan design for investment group professional staff and an expression of thanks to Alvah Chapman on his retirement from the Board.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2002 June 10 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Long Beach, CA on June 10, 2002. Included are notes of the level of risk the Board considers appropriate in the Community Partners Program, the decision to move the headquarters to the First Union Financial Center, and the nomination of Mariam Noland and Rob Briggs to the Board.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2002 September 10 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami on September 10, 2002. Included is an update on implementation of the new decentralized strategic plan and staff reports.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2002 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami on December 10, 2002. Included is a schedule and agenda; president's report; proposed community guidelines for 2003; proposed grant payout targets for 2003; direct charitable activity budgets (formerly known as Program Initiative Expenses); a move update; 2003 budget; and uKnight schedule.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2003 March 11 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        Minutes of the annual meeting of the trustees held in Miami, Florida. Emphasis was on committee reports.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2003 June 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Columbus, Georgia on June 10, 2003. Included are the minutes for a special meeting held June 9, 2003 re: approval of a grant for Columbus State University.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2003 September 9 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami on September 9, 2003. Included are reports from the committees, an update on Knight Foundation's potential investment in Oaktree Capital Management, and the search for two new trustees. A list of grants awarded, a memo from Hodding Carter re: payout increase, and a proposed restructuring of the Investment Department are also included.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2003 December 9 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami, Florida. Emphasis was on committee reports. Included is a list of grants approved; recommended grant payout targets for 2004; proposed community guidelines for 2004; 2004 budget and program narratives; a Review of Knight Foundation's September 11th Fund Grant Making; Community Partners, Journalism, and Venture Fund Program Updates; an Asset Allocation Proposal; and a current organization chart.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2004 March 9 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        Minutes of the annual meeting of the trustees held in Miami, Florida. Emphasis was on personnel changes: Penny McPhee's last board meeting; the search process for a new president and chief executive officer; appointment of Larry "Bud" Meyer as Secretary and the election of Bud Baker, Jr. to replace Gordon Heffern and Mary Sue Coleman to replace Jill Conway (in 2005) on the board. Also included are committee reports; discussion on planning for the new strategic plan and the National Venture Fund; the President's report; an organization chart; and committee assignments for March 2004-March 2005.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2004 June 15 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Philadelphia, PA. Includes an update on the presidential search committee, the nomination of James Crutchfield, president and publisher of the Akron Beacon-Journal to replace Mike Maidenberg on the Board of Trustees, other staff changes and committee reports. Also included are minutes of the special joint meeting of the Planning and Program and Grants Review Committees, a memo re: TCC interviews with planning and program committee members on questions for strategic planning, legal counsel Rod Petrey's memo on Federal Anti-Terrorist Laws, a current organization chart, and board resolutions (original copies are in folder), on succession designating Michael Maidenberg, Vice-President and CPO to serve as acting President in the event of the President's inability or refusal to act.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2004 September 12 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held by conference call (due to a hurricane threat) in Miami, FL. Includes reports of the Grants Review, Investment, Administrative and Human Resources and Audit committees. Appendices include a recent events update; updated organizational chart; sample revised employee work policy; sample whistleblower policy; insurance coverage summary; and audit committee charter.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2004 December 7 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees December 7, 2004 in Miami, FL. Includes reports of the Planning and Program, Investment, Administrative and Human Resources, Grants Review (includes grants approved) and Audit committees. Also discussed were committee appointments, the external audit, the executive search for a new president and the possibility of outsourcing the investment management function. Appendices include recommended grant payout targets for 2005; Direct Charitable Activities; Board meeting locations; KF organization chart; flexible benefit plan; 2005 budget; audit planning and committee charter; and a copy of the board resolution re: retirement of Jill Ker Conway.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2005 January 25 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        Minutes of a special board meeting to discuss a recommendation from the Investment Committee on the outsourcing of the Investment department. The board voted to outsource the work to Cambridge Associates.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2005 March 15 (Box 7, Folder 10)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees March 15, 2005 in Miami, FL. Includes reports of the Planning and Program, Investment, Pension, Administrative and Human Resources, Audit, Nominating, and Grants Review (includes grants approved). Also discussed were committee appointments, the community foundations initiative, and transition planning for the president/ceo. Appendices include: a strategic planning update, integrity of the voting system proposed initiative, exit strategies for Magic of Music and Museum Loan Network, investment committee materials, certificates of resolution, an organization chart and financial statements. Also Investment Management Agreement with Cambridge Associates.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2005 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 11)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees June 7, 2005 in Charlotte, NC. Includes reports of the Planning and Program, Investment, Administrative and Human Resources, Audit, and Grants Review (includes grants approved). Also discussed were accelerated transitioning for the president/ceo and the favorable investment transition to Cambridge Associates. Appendices include: investment committee materials, and the specific duties of the audit committee.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2005 September 19 (Box 7, Folder 12)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees September 19, 2005 in Miami, FL. [The meeting took place the day before scheduled due to concerns about Hurricane Rita] Includes reports of the Investment, Administrative and Human Resources, Audit, and Grants Review (includes grants approved). [The Planning and Program Committee meeting was cancelled due to the storm.] Discussed were recent activities of new president, Alberto Ibarguen; Cambridge Associates results; and a Risk Assessment Report prepared by the Nonprofit Risk Management Center. Appendices include: investment committee materials, and two resolutions.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2005 December 13 (Box 7, Folder 13)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees December 13, 2005 in Miami, FL. Includes reports of the Planning and Program, Investment, Administrative and Human Resources, Audit, Nominating, and Grants Review (includes grants approved). Included is a copy of KF's new privacy policy; recent events summary; and 2006 budget. The resignation of trustee Bud Baker in October, due to absenteeism, was noted.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2006 March 14 (Box 7, Folder 14)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees March 14, 2006 in Miami, FL. Includes reports of the Planning and Program, Investment, Administrative and Human Resources, Audit, Nominating, and Grants Review (includes grants approved). Includes discussion of the Knight Ridder sale, resolution to add a class C of trustee to allow for the service of the KF president on the board during his term in office; a recent events summary; and a report on the audit prepared by Ernst and Young.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2006 June 13 (Box 7, Folder 15)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees June 13, 2006 in Miami, FL. Includes reports of the Planning and Program, Investment, Administrative and Human Resources, Audit, Nominating, and Grants Review (includes grants approved). Includes committee chair assignments; election of three new trustees: Earl Powell, Roe Stamps, and Paul Steiger; KF branding project; approved changes in trustee compensation; Update in the trustees' meeting schedule, commitee composition and compensation; and a recent events summary.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2006 September 12 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees September 12, 2006 in Detroit, MI. Includes a board decision to continue working in all Knight communities. Special preference is to be given to the original 12 Knight newspaper communities. For certain communities, not in the original 12, staff is to develop ways to maintain a community funding presence through community advisory committees and community foundations. Paula Ellis was named as Vice President of New and National Initiatives. The board heard reports from the program (including approval of $5 million from the Transformation Fund for the Knight Brothers 21st Century News Challenge); governance (formerly Administration and Human Resources); and audit committees.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2006 December 4 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees December 4, 2006 in Miami, FL. Includes a report on changes to the foundation's senior management team, establishment of an executive committee, and reports from the program, investment, and audit committees. Attachments include a list of grants approved by the president and the board,
      - Meeting Minutes, 2007 March 12 (Box 8, Folder 3)
        Contains schedule, agenda and minutes. Includes committee reports, and list of approved grants. Also included is a memo from Paula Ellis re: Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics: Executive Summary of History, Goals and Results.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2007 June 4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami, FL. Minutes include committee reports, a list and description of approved grants, and an attachment concerning Knight's policy on business travel and expense reimbursement. Also included is a meeting schedule and agenda.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2007 September 16 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        Schedule, agenda and minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in San Jose, CA.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2007 December 10 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        Schedule, agenda and minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami, FL. Included are committee reports; a revision of KF's Investment Policy; and a resolution re: naming Trabian Shorters as VP/Communities Program.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 March 10 (Box 8, Folder 7)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami, FL. Included are committee reports; a list of approved grants; and a resolution re: naming Marc Fest as VP/Communications Program.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 June 9 (Box 8, Folder 8)
        Minutes of the quarterly meeting of the trustees held in Miami, FL. Included are committee reports; a list of approved grants; and amendments 1st and 5th and resolution re: retirement plan for employees of Knight Foundation.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 September 14 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        Minutes and agenda for meeting held at the Newseum Museum in Washington, DC. Includes committee reports, and community survey results. The board also approved the creation of a trustee sub-committee to discuss strategic planning. Also provided is a summary of grants, memo about indemnification of Trustees and officers and an updated copy of KF's 403(b) plan.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 December 8 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        Minutes of meeting held in Miami, FL. Includes committee reports; summary of grants approved, approved by president, recommended as part of the Information Needs Initiative, and rejected by staff; an analysis of grant distributions based on KF funding policy for 2008/2009; a list of multi-year grant commitments; and a GandA budget analysis for 2008/2009. Also included is a discussion document prepared by McKinsey and Associates to facilitate discussion on KF's effort to restate the vision and ground the strategy to have greater impact while preserving donor intent.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 March 9 (Box 8, Folder 11)
        Minutes of meeting held in Miami, FL, including committee reports, and a strategy discussion. Also included is a resolution of the Board of Trustees to add the position of Chair-Elect to the Board instead of a Vice Chair, with the understanding that the Chair-Elect shall succeed the Chair upon the latter's retirement and a discussion document prepared by McKinsey and Associates re: strategies for Journalism and Community-based grants.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 June 8 (Box 8, Folder 12)
        Meeting minutes, agenda and schedule for the June 2009 Board of Trustees meeting, held in Miami, FL. Also included are some materials distributed at the board meeting but not included as part of the official minutes: Grants for discussion (trustee questions and staff responses); expanded schedule and agenda; memo from Juan Martinez re: alternative methods for managing endowments; news article on the Newseum; remarks by Damian Thorman re: mergers and Paula Ellis re: Gallup Update; conflict of interest for grant proposals; Strategic Assessment and Impact Work Plan PowerPoint; Questions for Knight Foundation Trustees; and CONFIDENTIAL Knight strategic direction discussion document.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 September 13-14 (Box 8, Folder 13)
        Meeting agenda and schedule for the September 2009 Board of Trustees meeting, held in Akron, OH. Also included is a white paper, prepared by The Baller Herbst Law Group, entitled "OneCommunity and the Knight Center of Digital Excellence: An Important Model for America's Broadband Revival". The paper was commissioned by OneCommunity and its Knight Center of Digital Excellence to analyze their programs and suggest ways to enhance or strengthen them. The minutes include information on the Knight Community Information Challenge evaluation plan; committee reports; summary of grants approved and rejected; and a summary of proposals recommended for approval.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 December 7 (Box 8, Folder 14)
        Meeting schedule and minutes for the December 2009 Board of Trustees meeting, held in Miami, FL. Also included is a memo from Alberto Ibarguen re: KF structure and reorganization of the KF communities; a chart dividing the KF-supported Community Foundations by size of community and listing total assets, population, and initiative amounts; General and Administrative Analysis for the proposed 2010 budget; summary of grants approved by President and inquiries and proposals rejected by staff.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 15 (Box 8, Folder 15)
        Minutes of meeting, as well as a nominating committee report; summary of grants approved and rejected; trustee committee assignments; and 2011 meeting dates. Also included is a confidential Grantee Perception Report (full and excerpt for Board), prepared by the Center for Effective Philanthropy, which was reviewed while the Board was meeting in Executive Session; and a resolution naming Dennis Scholl Vice President/Arts.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 June 14 (Box 8, Folder 16)
        Minutes of meeting, including charts of summaries of grants approved and rejected.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 September 13 (Box 8, Folder 17)
        Minutes of meeting in Charlotte, NC. Also included are agenda and schedule and a memo from Juan Martinez and Jennifer Thomas re: status update on the Austen BioInnovation Institute in Akron, OH.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 December 13 (Box 8, Folder 18)